

My Design Process

Empathy

Understanding of the problem I'm trying to solve.

Define

Analyze and synthesis my observations.

Ideate

Brainstorm and Worst & Best Possible Idea Sessions.

Design

Wireframe, Creating Style Guide & Components, UI Design, and Rapid Prototype.

Test

Collecting Feedback, Understanding of user, the conditions of use, how people think, behave, and feel, and to empathise.

Skills

User Research

Business Ideation

Design Strategy

Wireframe

UI/UX Design

Prototyping

Design System

Reusable Components

HTML5

CSS3

JavaSceipt

Scrum

Sadman Sakib Jisan

UI / UX Design & Development

+8801675 89 39 67 · ssjisan.dev@gmail.com

With 1.5 years of experience as a UI/UX Designer and Developer, I have a strong foundation in user-centered design principles and proficiency in design tools like Adobe XD, and Figma. I can create visually appealing wireframes, prototypes, and high-fidelity designs, and implement responsive and interactive interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Work Experience



Executive, UI / UX Design & Development BYSL Global Technology Group

February, 2022 - Present • Full Time

BYSL Global Technology Group is a next-generation technology conglomerate. The group operates as an integrated business ecosystem with investments in multiple brands, industries, markets, and supply chains. A fast-growth organization built on a forward-thinking culture of learning, teamwork, and integrity, embracing change and fueling innovation.

Responsibilities (UI / UX Designer)

- Translate user behavior and research into actionable data
- Make ideas, wireframes, and mockups that lead to intuitive client encounters
- Design and create mockups and client ventures for many gadgets including mobile
- Gather and evaluate user requirements in collaboration with product manager / project manager and front-end developers
- Develop UI mockups and prototypes that clearly illustrate how sites function and look like
- Identify and troubleshoot UX problems
- Conduct layout adjustments based on user feedback.
- Design, build, and maintain highly reusable React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS code



Front-end Developer Techhack Canada

September, 2021 - January, 2022 • Full Time

Techhack is a Canadian startup. It's a developer hiring platform. Initially, there is a plan that Canadian companies can hire developers from Bangladesh, but later that plan-track change to launch it on a larger scale. Various assessments are arranged for the developers. After completing the assessment, the recruiter will get an idea about the skills of a developer. I was appointed as a front end developer in this company.

Tools

Brainstorming / Ideation

Figma

Design

Figma, Adobe XD

Protorype

Figma

Dev Handoff

Figma

Project Management

Clickup, Trello, Cliqapp

Communication

Skpe, Google Meet, Chat, Zoom, Discord

Education

B.Sc Engineer at Computer Science & Engineering

University of Science & Technology, Chittagong

Responsibilities (Front-end Developer)

- Understanding the user experience
- · Prototyping the flow with figma
- Planning and Implementation of Project Flow
- Converting the UI part with React.js, Material UI
- Creating reusable component with React.js
- Ensure responsiveness for every screen
- Rest api integration
- Collaborating with backend development team



Front-end Developer Eric Frank India

December, 2020 - January, 2020 - Part Time Remote

Eric Frank India is a company that has created an innovative fundraising platform connecting startups with venture capitalists. Through their streamlined process, startups can apply for investment and showcase their ideas to potential investors, while venture capitalists can discover and invest in promising startups. Eric Frank India's commitment to personalized service and support makes them a trusted partner for startups seeking to access the capital they need to grow.

Responsibilities (Front-end Developer)

- Designed the user interface (UI) for a fund raising platform using design tools like Figma and Bootstrap
- Maintained user experience (UX) and ensured it was intuitive and efficient
- Created wireframes to plan and visualize the system flow and user journey
- Developed the platform using React.js, HTML, CSS, and other front-end technologies
- Collaborated with the back-end development team to integrate the front-end with the database and APIs
- Conducted user testing and gathered feedback to improve the design and functionality of the platform
- Managed version control and maintained documentation for the project.